which went on for nearly a quarter of an hour and put an end to any chance of
discussion.
Afterwards, Squealer was sent round the farm to explain the new arrangement to the others.
"Comrades, I trust that every animal here appreciates the sacrifice that
Comrade Napoleon has made in taking this extra labor upon himself.
Do not imagine, comrades, that leadership is a pleasure. On the contrary, it is a deep and heavy
responsibility. No one believes more firmly than Comrade Napoleon that all
animals are equal. He would be only too happy to let you make your decisions for
yourselves, but sometimes you might make the wrong decisions, comrades, and then
where should we be?
Suppose you had decided to follow Snowball with his moonshine of
windmills, Snowball, who, as we now know, was no better than a criminal.
He fought bravely at the Battle of the Cowshed.
"Bravery is not enough. Loyalty and obedience are more important. And as to
the Battle of the Cowshed, I believe the time will come when we shall find that
Snowball's part in it was much exaggerated.
Discipline, comrades, iron discipline, that is the watchword for today. One
false step and our enemies would be upon us. Surely, comrades, you do not want Jones back.
>> Once again, this argument was unanswerable.
Certainly, the animals did not want Jones back. If the holding of debates on
Sunday mornings was liable to bring him back, then the debates must stop.
Boxer, who had now had time to think things over, voiced the general feeling by saying,
>> "If comrade Napoleon says it, it must be right."
>> And from then on, he adopted the maxim, "Napoleon is always right."